So let's take a quick look at how grid and flexbox can work together.
لنلق نظرة سريعة على كيفية عمل الشبكة والصندوق المرن معًا.
To start, I'm going to show you an example that I've
بداية، سأعرض أمثلة أعددتها
made and take you through it quickly,
وأشرحها بشكل سريع،
but the truth is, you're going to learn how to build
وستتعلمون كيفية إنشاء
this up step-by-step throughout the lesson.
مثل هذا المثال خلال الدرس.
As you can see here,
كما نرى هنا،
I've set up a grid using a container.
أنشأت شبكة باستخدام حاوية.
The first thing I've done is I've set the display to grid.
أول خطوة هي ضبط خاصية العرض على شبكة (grid).
We'll go through the columns and rows coming up.
سنستعرض الأعمدة والصفوف لاحقًا
You can see I've set grid template areas,
تلاحظون أني ضبطت مناطق قالب الشبكة.
and here, each box uses the display flex.
وهنا يستخدم كل مربع خاصية العرض المرن (flex).
Here's our HTML, three boxes, inside a container.
وهنا برمجة HTML لثلاثة مربعات داخل حاوية.
The container has a display of grid and each box has a display of flex.
تم ضبط خاصية العرض للحاوية على شبكة، وكل مربع على العرض المرن.
That's what's putting these words here in the middle.
ولهذا السبب تظهر هذه الكلمات في الوسط.
If you see, once we take flex away,
ولكن عند حذف خاصية العرض المرن،
all of our content is put back up into the top left-hand corner.
يظهر المحتوى في الزاوية العلوية اليسرى.
However, with flex, we can center them easily.
يمكن توسيط المحتوى بسهولة باستخدام خاصية المرونة.
Now, there's just one more trick I want to show you,
وهناك حيلة أخرى أريد أن أعرضها لكم،
and this one makes me really excited.
وهي ما تشعرني بالحماس فعلًا.
So as you can see in our grid here,
نلاحظ في هذه الشبكة هنا،
the distribution is a little funny.
أن التوزيع يبدو غريبًا بعض الشيء.
Everything is kind of leaning to the left, but grid,
فكل شيء يميل نحو اليسار، ولكن الشبكة،
like flex, allows you to justify your content using justify content.
مثل فليكس، تمكنك من ضبط المحتوى باستخدام خاصية ضبط المحتوى.
In this case, I want to see centered.
في هذه الحالة، سنضبط المحتوى على توسيط،
So let's save that and then look at that.
ثم نحفظ التغييرات ونلقي نظرة.
Now we have a beautiful laid out grid,
أصبحت الشبكة الآن مرتبة بشكل جميل،
two columns and two rows,
يوجد عمودان وصفّان،
all put beautifully in the middle.
جميعها تتموضع بالوسط.
This is just one example of what you can do using CSS grid and flexbox together.
هذا مثال واحد وحسب على ما يمكن القيام به باستخدام فليكس بوكس وشبكة CSS معًا.